André Lucas de Sousa Pinto

Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

portfolio.andrelucax.com · linkedin.com/in/andrelucax · github.com/andrelucax andrelucax@gmail.com · +55 (61) 98231-4376 · 28 Years old · Brazil



Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering from the University of Brasília (UnB). Experienced in designing secure, well-tested, and scalable softwares using agile methodologies. Enthusiastic about web, mobile and game development, as well as home automation.

EDUCATION

Universidade de Brasília DF, Brazil
Software Engineer 2017 - 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

09/2021 - Present

Full Stack Developer | Lacuna Software | Brazil

Developed software for registration authorities following ICP-Brasil standards, engaging in all stages of development, from requirement gathering and analysis to client meetings, database modeling, backend, frontend, and testing. Implemented various features including video conferencing, biometric data collection, digital certificate issuance, digital signature, and automatic email sending. Established unit, integration, and end-to-end testing standards adopted as the company's project basis. Contributed to existing projects by developing new functions, maintenance, code improvements and bug fixes. Designed a standard for multi-tenant applications and created a real-time communication system for biometric authentication validation. Additionally, updated .NET and Angular frameworks for various systems, including the company's foundational project.

03/2021 - 08/2021

Intern | Federal Court of Accounts (TCU) | Brazil

Developed new applications and maintained existing ones, enhancing team performance and transparency.

09/2020 - 02/2021

Intern | Companhia da Terra | Brazil

Developed a companion app for the pet shop, enabling customers to receive reminders for their pets' medications and vaccines, thereby increasing store sales and improving pets' lives.



SKILLS

Languages C# | JavaScript | TypeScript | C++ | C | Python | SQL | HTML | CSS | Languages

Databases MSSQL | Postgres | Oracle SQL

Frameworks & Libraries .NET | ASP.NET | EF | SignalR | Playwright | MSTest | XUnit | Angular | Django | Django

Restframework | React | React Native

Tools Docker | Git | AWS | Figma | Jira

Spoken Languages Native Portugues | Advanded English

Others REST | Swagger | CI/CD | Clean Code | Microservices | Distributed Systems | Frontend |

Backend | Full Stack

CERTIFICATES & GRANTS

2023 From Zero to Hero: Unit testing for C# Developers2023 From Zero to Hero: Integration testing in ASP.NET Core



